As we've worked through the
presentation and the word processing
unit so far, you've seen me
carry out a range of activities.
In the workplace, you can be
assigned a task and you could
be given a deadline for that.
One of the most important things
to do is when you have been given a
task is to plan it out effectively.
It may be a case that you are given
an assignment brief, or you're given
instructions in an email or in a document.
And you have to create a presentation.
You have to create a newsletter.
You have to create letters, forms,
a poster it could be anything.
One of the easiest ways to ensure that
you do this successfully is to plan out
a task and make sure that you've got
all the information before you start.
So for example, In the PowerPoint, I've
been asked to create a presentation
that will demonstrate the Flyaway
balloon rides, the success so far,
and to give everybody an idea of
the growth the company has seen.
So the first thing I need to do is
when you look at the information
you need to think about so
what is the information I need?
Well I've been given that information.
Is there any additional
information that I need and where
would I get that information?
So for example, all the information
has been provided within this Word
document and I could just clarify that
with the management team or whoever
had given me the actual information to
confirm that it was accurate/up to date.
Is there any additional information?
But I also needed the images.
So where would access the images from?
Just to make sure that I've got
everything I need that is to be
placed inside of the presentation.
And then obviously the software choice
as well, that can depend obviously with
relating to the PowerPoint presentation.
It was quite obvious the choice would be
PowerPoint, but I could be being asked to
create something and say well, this may
be better in a handout so a document that
would have a report, could be a letter.
I could provide it in a brochure format
or there's a variety of different formats.
And so you'd need to look at what
you've been asked to do, and then that
will inform your software choices, so
if it's primarily going to be data and
financial figures, you would use Excel.
If you've got to give information to
a group of people in an audience, you
may find that a PowerPoint is the most
appropriate, or again, it may be a case
that a letter or a newsletter or poster.
They would be more effective in
conveying the information to people.
And you also need to think about, well,
what skills and resources do you need?
So obviously you would need the
software and you would need the
skills to use that software.
So it's no good being given a task in
relation to a spreadsheet and being asked
to provide some complex calculations
within there if you're not familiar
with using spreadsheet software and
the features and functions within that.
Similarly, if you're not familiar with
a lot of the tools within Word and
PowerPoint, so you need to ensure that you
have the skills and resources to do that.
And if not, then you have to try
and identify how you can get those
skills and the resources to that.
And also the other thing to think about
is when you've got that information,
plan out how you're going to set it out.
As you can see in the Word document, that
contains information for the presentation.
I can see there that I've already
selected that it's going to be the
title slide which is slide one.
That's what it's going to contain.
Slide two and slide three,
and then slide four.
How am I going to structure that?
Well, as you can see, I've got each
slide has got a title and it's got
some text content, and then I've got
some information which as you will
have seen I will put that into a table
format and then you can also include
charts and graphs, add some animation.
So again, you've got to think about
how you're going to present that
information and it's easier to do
it if you already know that and
you've planned that out in advance.
And again, the last thing to think
about is what's your priorities?
So.
It could be a deadline.
It could be a case that you need to
have the information to a manager or
a client within a certain timeframe.
So it's always important to ensure
that you've got your priorities.
Gathering the information is priority one.
And then making sure that you've got the
correct software, the skills or resources,
and again, but you tend to find that the
most important priority is the timeframe
that you have to complete the task within.
So all these things need to be considered
when you're planning out a task.
And when you've been assigned a task
and by planning it out effectively, will
ensure that it improves the productivity
and efficiency because it takes less
time to actually get the product
to the client or to your manager or
colleague who requires that information.